Never forget why you are the church.
I want you to turn your Bible to Revelation chapter 8.
Revelation chapter eight.
We're going to be in this chapter for the majority of the night.
We're going to jump around a little bit.
Kiddos, if you don't have a Bible, there's Bibles in the back on
those tables that you can use, so you
can do that if you want.
And if you don't have a Bible.
By the way, you are free to take those home.
I'm looking into getting
some newer Bibles that are hard back that
don't get so beat up like those are and even maybe even putting Cedar Girl Baptist Church on the front and stuff.
So we'll probably have it, you know, some cabinets
on each corner, and we'll calm our Bible
cabinets because we don't have the things in the chairs.
So, uh, we want to we want to make sure that if someone wants access
to God's word that we are a catalyst for that and not a hindrance of that.
So, but anyway, that's awesome seeing all the kids go, that's really cool.
By the way, welcome kids.
I'm glad y'all with us tonight.
Yeah?
You glad to be here?
Let
me just get the preaching so we can get done with that.
Anyway, um, we're
looking at the events that will take place in the 7 year tribulation,
but before we even get to that,
Um, there's a there's a little
part in between that I really got stuck on today as
I was studying.
But in Revelation chapter 8, we see the 7th seal is broken and
the 7 trumpets were revealed.
Now in lesson 4, we went over the 7,
the 6 of the 7 seals.
Okay?
So if you want to go back and figure
that out, you can go use our CGBC media player and do that.
But this tonight, we're going to look at verse one and two.
It says, and when he had opened the 7th seal, there
was silence in heaven about the space of a half in an hour.
In other words, 30 minutes or half an hour, sorry.
And I saw the 7 angels which stood before God, and
to them were given 7 trumpets.
So we see here that the 7 trumpets are about to be sounded.
This is going to be an uptick in the tribulation
part of the great tribulation.
So let's pray, Father, we thank you, Lord, for this night.
We thank you for your word.
We thank you that we're able to gather freely according to your word, God.
Be with us, God.
Teach us, Lord, in Jesus' name, pray.
Amen.
These trumpets are explained in a more brief manner,
then the seals.
However, we see some interesting details to set
up the thirst of the 7 trumpets sounding.
If you look at Revelation chapter 8, verses
3 through five, this is what it says.
And another angel.
So we see here in verse two, there's 7 angels which
stood before God, and they were giving 7 trumpets, and
then we see another angel came and stood at the altar having a golden censer.
And there was given unto him much incense that
he should offer it with the prayers of all saints upon the golden altar,
which was before the throne.
And the smoke of the incense, which came with the prayers
of the saints, ascended up before God out of the angel's hand.
And the angel took the censer and filled it with fire of the
altar and cast it into the earth, and there were voices and
thunderings and lightnings and an earthquake.
Now, if you're not careful, you
read this and you read these 3 verses and you skip right onto
the trumpet sounding and all the devastation that
happens on the earth when they do.
But I want us to 1st notice, there is another angel here.
Now, some believe this to be the glorified
Lord, which is not impossible by any means.
However, if you look at the term another, it
can mean both another, but different or another,
but the same, the fact that there is no specific
indication that this is Jesus means that we should see
this angel as another angel with a different assignment.
So in other words, this angel is not given a trumpet,
but rather a censor, okay?
Again, this is the 1st and only mention of a
sensor on in Revelation.
Now, I kind of dug a little deep on this.
sensors were used in the Old Testament to carry coals from
the brazen altar outside of the tabernacle, to
the altar of incense inside the tabernacle.
The Old Testament tabernacle senses would have been made of copper.
They were very heavy, very, very difficult to
carry later in the temple that Solomon built.
They were of pure gold.
This brings up the importance and meaning of burning
incense.
Now, this practice goes all the
way back to the Great Exodus from Egypt.
Now, if you remember, what was the request made
from Moses to Pharaoh?
Let my people go.
But there's some details on why.
For example, I don't know, does anyone watch Star Wars?
Yeah?
Do y'all like Star Wars?
Okay.
What is Darth Vader's famous saying?
Darth Vaders, you know.
Hold on, what is it?
All right, I'm about to blow your minds right here.
You know he does not say Luke.
He says, no, I am your father.
Taylor,
don't don't patronize me like that.
But what I'm trying to tell you, look, so we see here,
we look at the reason
that this is happening, sometimes we can see, just like in the movie,
we think, man, we thought this is what it was about the entire time.
There's shirts.
There's people that say it.
I know somebody that named their child, Luke, so
they could say, Luke, I am your father.
You understand what I'm saying?
So but here, we got to look at the details, okay?
Exodus chapter 5, verse one says this.
And afterward, Moses and Aaron came
and said the pharaoh, thus says the Lord, the God of
Israel, let my people go.
That, they may celebrate a
feast to me in the wilderness.
The deliverance of the Hebrews
from the captivity of Egypt is one
of the most mentioned events in all the Bible, yet often we
forget why God orchestrated the whole thing in the 1st place.
The purpose of the exodus was
for God's people to have the freedom to worship God without
restriction.
Now, I want to connect this to our lives
today because I can't go any further, the connection is so strong here.
The purpose of our freedom in Christ is
not to do what we want is not to abuse grace,
is not just to sin because now we're saved, and we can get away with it.
That's not the purpose of why God forgave us and
delivered us and saved us.
The purpose is that we could freely worship
him.
And so we are saved, delivered from our sin,
no longer captives to our sin for the sole purpose
of worshiping God.
We were created to worship our creator,
and that is the almighty God.
That should by the way, put our life in a little bit of perspective.
When you start getting distracted about this and that and
these goals and these ambitions.
Listen, goals and ambitions are good, but if it's not centered
around a life that worships Christ, and what are we even doing?
We're living outside the reason of our purpose being here.
So we see the great Exodus,
and once they cross the Red Sea, they built a tabernacle
or a tent, rather, that was used for worship throughout
the 40 year wilderness journey.
It was inside this tent that
they burn incense to the Lord.
The rising smoke signified the worship
of the Israelites ascending to God.
Its aroma depicted his acceptance and pleasure of their devotion.
Now, here's the thing though.
Here's the interesting, and this is kind of the deep dive here.
Now we know that in order to get a certain aroma.
There must be ingredients.
Amen?
My favorite thing about fall, okay?
I know we're going right in the summer and like, why are you talking my fault?
My favorite thing, one of my favorite things about fall and winter is does anyone
do little things where they put the like the oranges and the citrus
things and the little cinnamon sticks?
And man, that is some of the best smells ever, but
it's specific to what you put in the pot.
So you got to get a specific,
uh, uh, you know, ingredient to get the aroma
that you want.
So, for those that smoke meat,
anyone smoke meat in here?
Anyone like to smoke meat?
Who likes to eat smoked meat?
Amen, everybody.
Okay, right.
Listen, depending on what kind of wood or chips you use
or whatever it is, right?
Like that will change the taste, change the smell of what is going on.
You say, what in the world is this about?
Well, God gives clear and specific instructions
on the very blend that burn inside the tabernacle.
We see this in Exodus chapter
30, verse 34 through 35, it says this.
Then the Lord said to Moses, take for yourselves spices.
Now, there's 3 spices here that
I have no idea how to say.
Okay?
I'm going to try, kiddos.
You can listen to this, you don't have
I mean, it's going to be kind of a bad situation, but stackedy,
S-T-A-C-T-E, stackedy, uh,
onitcha, onitcha.
You know what I'm talking about, Bill?
Onicher?
You got some of that in your house?
Yeah, that's what it's, you know, Anache.
Galbinum, right?
Now, I can say this.
with pure frankincense and there will be an equal part of each.
So in other words, God is telling Moses, listen, you're going to go to the tabernacle.
You're going to burn incense and it's going to be a sweet smelling savor
to me in aroma, but you have to be very specific in how you do it.
These are the ingredients.
With all this, you should make incense, a perfume, the
work of a perfume, salted, pure, and holy.
Each ingredient has its purpose
and reason for being mentioned.
We won't go over each one tonight, but God assigned the
high priest, the role of burning this particular blend on the altar
of incense.
This was done twice daily, once before the morning sacrifice.
And another time before the evening sacrifice.
But there's a special time for instance, that took
place on a day of atonement.
Now, we know that Israel, by God's command,
there was many days of celebrations and festivities and
solemn days, they had to recognize
and perform throughout the year.
And the day of atonement was the most solemn day on
their calendar, okay?
The day of atonement was very important.
It was the day once a year that they performed certain rituals
to atone for the sins of the people.
In other words, they would offer the incense.
They would offer the sacrifice for the forgiveness
of the people's sin.
By the way, if you're in here, I want you to know something.
That's what Jesus was for us.
So you have a sacrifice after sacrifice
after sacrifice in the Old Testament.
God sent his son, Jesus, because he loved us so much,
and he wanted to make a way of our salvation, and
he was the final sacrifice, the final sweet smelling
aroma that God desired for our salvation.
So that's a pretty cool thing right there.
But it was on a day of atonement that the high priest entered the holy
of holies with incense and a censor.
The smoke from this incense created a protective cloud over
the mercy seat which covered the ark of the covenant.
The smoke symbolized the prayers
of the people and protected the high priest from the direct presence of God.
Now, throughout scripture, instance
is used to represent worship and a pleasing aroma to the Lord.
According to Exodus 30, verse 36 and 37,
it was to be holy, right?
It says this, you shall beat some of it very fine and
put part of it before the testimony in the tent, a meeting where I will meet you.
It shall be most holy to you.
The incense which you shall make, you shall not make
in the same proportions for yourself.
It shall be holy for you to you for the Lord.
This blend was to be used only for the Lord and not for personal use.
It was a sacred set apart situation here.
As a matter of fact, we see that if you did not
even use the right blend.
If you didn't listen to God's commands on how to make this.
Look what it says.
whoever shall make any like it, to
use his perfume shall be cut off from his people.
You shall not offer any strange incense on
this altar, a burnt offering or meal offering, and you shall not pour
out a drink offering on it.
In other words, God was very specific to what he desired.
We fast forward
to the New Testament, it was Zachariah, the father of John the Baptist,
who had been selected for the yearly placing of incense at the altar.
While he was doing this, the people were
gathered outside praying.
And I know I'm skipping around here, but David really
summarized this practice and principle of incense in Psalm 141.2.
May my prayer be counted as incense before you,
the lifting up my hands as the evening offering.
So this is this is connected to our prayers in
our worship of the Lord.
So now is the question, you might
be thinking, man, what a deep dive.
possibly, just one book further,
be the furthest place we can get from Revelation, right?
We've been in Exodus.
So how in the world does this relate to the study of the end times?
Why are we talking about Exodus 30 if we're talking about Revelation eight?
And I know you've been asking that politely in your head and not out loud.
I appreciate that.
What in the world does this have to do with what we're talking about?
Well, I think it's important that the Bible
may be a collection of 66 books that span different continents,
that have many different authors, that are
framed around many different cultures and time frames, yet it all
interconnects.
What we were talking about just in an Exodus
is extremely relevant to what we're
talking about tonight in Revelation 8.
We just talked about in length about the burning of incense
and what it means in the worship of God.
That was in Exodus.
Now look at Revelation 8, 3 through 5 again, and another
angel came and stood at the altar.
having a golden sense, and there was given unto him much incense
that he should offer it.
With the prayers of all the saints upon the golden
altar, which was before the throne.
And the smoke of the incense, which came with the prayers
of the saints, ascended up before God out of the angels' hands.
I don't want us to miss this tonight.
Remember one of the most critical details of incense was the blend?
that was burned.
Get the blend wrong
and it's an act of irreverence to God.
Right?
Don't follow God's command on this and you're
disrespecting the Lord.
By the way, to live in disobedience to the commands
of God is to live in a lack of fear and reverence towards God.
Jesus made it very clear, if you love me,
keep my commandments.
And by the way, the incense was
burned to offer forgiveness of their sins.
In other words, God's commandments to us,
kiddos, you need to hear this too.
God's commandments to us are not to create limitations
on our life or not to create us being miserable people.
They are to protect us from danger.
Right?
And so we see here that you
get the blend wrong and that's not a good thing.
So what do we see is in this sense of, well, it is
offered with the prayer of the saints.
The prayer of the saints.
Now, look back at Revelations 5, eight.
I know you're not there, but just listen.
And when he had taken the book,
The 4 beasts and 4 and 20 elders
fell down before the lamb, having every
one of them harps and hear this, and golden
bowels full of odors, which are the prayers of the saints.
Let's look at Psalm
141, verse 2 again, my prayer may my prayer be counted as incense before you.
The lifting up my hands as the evening offering.
So what is the blend that we see here?
What is the sacred blend of this?
It is the prayers of the saints throughout history.
Every time you have prayed according
to God's will, it has gone into the censor.
Now I can't even fathom that.
I can't even, I can't even understand that fully.
But I sure do like it.
Amen.
Listen, I like how the new American commentary
explains who these saints are.
The word translated saints means
most basically the holy ones.
Once again, this is not to be understood
as a separate category of Christ's followers who
have somehow achieved greater sanctity or ecclesiastical
recognition than others.
These are men and women who have been made holy through the
experience of repentance towards God and faith in
the Lord Jesus Christ and the accompanying regeneration, ministry of the Holy Spirit.
The word is used in both the departed dead,
who have died in Christ as well as the living, regenerate individuals.
In other words, all the saints for the history of time, those who have
put their faith in Christ Jesus.
That's what we're talking about here.
We're talking about our prayers.
We're talking about your saved mama and daddy's prayers.
Your saved grandma and grandpa's prayers.
That's what we're talking about here.
How awesome is that?
When you prayed for your loved one's salvation that went in.
When you pray for the safety of people, when you
prayed for healing, when you pray for God to use you and
change you and transform you to his will, all
these prayers go into the censor, and such prayers are
a pleasing aroma to God.
Now why is this important?
Our prayers are not just her, they are stored.
Now that's interesting to me.
Here's the thing.
They are precious to God.
Have you ever kept anything that's precious to you?
Anyone got any keepsakes in their life?
Listen, I am I am just about a hoarder.
Okay?
Y'all have given me stuff over the years that I still have.
You know what I'm saying?
and I won't get rid of, you know?
I love keepsakes.
I love things that mean something.
And every time I look at it and see it, it just it
reminds me of that something.
It reminds me of how precious it is.
If you've ever had kids.
I don't know if you're like this, but we have the hair of their 1st haircut, right?
Not all of it.
Okay, that'd be kind of odd.
But like, you know, we have like just a strand of their hair for the 1st haircut.
It's precious to us.
We got it in a little plastic baggy.
We'll never get rid of it
You understand what I'm saying?
Uh, River.
I was not expecting her being here tonight.
So, you know, part of being a PK.
But anyway, you know, she's lost both her front teeth, right?
Well, we were at the pool on Monday night and
she had this one, man.
It was jacked up.
I mean, it was like, you know, crooked and she, you know, she likes to let the tooth
just really get to the point of where it's like, man, this is kind of getting inappropriate.
You know what I'm saying?
Like we need to pull this tooth.
And so we were at the pool and my
dad, listen, he is, there's no, well, I'm
going to be careful my language here.
He loves pulling teeth.
Okay?
He pays good for teeth.
All right?
I mean, I'm not going to,
Hey, listen, some of y'all get $one, like, it ain't no $one.
Just put it that way.
But I told, I said, man, listen, I told River, I said,
River, let your boss, just pull your tooth,
man, it means so much to him.
She's like, no, I don't want to.
I'm like, well, I can't force you, but I really like you to do it.
Well, we're around the pool.
And all of a sudden,
River turns around and her
mouth is just bleeding all over her chin.
And he's like, boss, pull my tooth like that right there.
Now listen, here's the craziest thing about it.
Boss said this, let me just wiggle it.
Boss ain't wiggled a tooth his entire life.
There's no wiggling of the, there is only plucking
of the teeth out of your mouth, okay?
But either way, guess what happened?
He went like this, he pulled it.
Guess what we couldn't find?
The tooth.
We are out there with our little flashlight.
I mean, I'm talking about on all 4s for like 45 minutes.
sun is going down
Looking in the grass.
Look, and I don't know if you checked the filters in the pool, but like we have looked.
Wow.
Because there's certain things in life that
are precious enough to keep and to store.
Okay, now I don't know if you're someone that keeps in stores teeth.
I know that that's probably a serial killer thing, so we don't want to do that.
But either way, it's precious when it's your kid's teeth.
But here's the thing.
Your constant prayers may seem trivial at times.
They may seem like they're hitting a dead end road in heaven.
People may look at you wondering, why are you still praying for that?
You need to never forget that your prayers are precious to the Lord.
But then we see there's a purpose also to
the prayers of the saints.
In Revelation 8, verse 5.
And the angel took the censor and filled it with the fire of the altar and cast it into the earth.
And there were voices and thunderings and lightnings
in an earthquake.
Now, we don't want to overhype this.
What this is, is this is anticipation.
This is a buildup.
This is a buildup of expectation, is the answer to the
cries of the martyrs in Revelation 610, and they cried
out with a loud voice saying, how long, O Lord, holy and true,
will you refrain from judging and avenging our blood on
those who dwell on the earth?
This is the moment.
This is the buildup to God is going to bring judicial appointment of
wrath to the entire earth.
This is the beginning of the 7 trumpet sounding.
Every midweek, We pray for our people.
No matter what the sickness or disease is, no matter the tragedy,
you or someone in your love is enduring.
When we pray in the will of God, our prayers are stored, not just
her, but stored an expectation of all the things becoming new.
So my question now is, have you given up
on certain prayers?
Maybe you've given up on praying
for that loved one or praying for that spouse or praying for that, or
praying for that situation or praying for for
the healing, whatever it is, have you given up and think, you know what, God doesn't care.
All the way at the end
of the book, we see that he cares.
All the way to the end.
We see that he has stored the precious prayers of his saints.
That's us.